epilogue.
And I only am escaped alone to tell thee. Job.
The drama's done. Why then here does anyone step forth? Because one did survive the wreck.
It's so chance that after the Parsey's disappearance, I was he whom the fates
ordained to take the place of Ahab's bowsman, when that bowsman assumed the
vacant post, the same who, when, on the last day the three men were tossed from
out of the rocking boat, was dropped a stern. So floating on the margin of the
ensuing scene, and in full sight of it, when the half- spent suction of the sunk
ship reached me, I was then but slowly drawn towards the closing vortex. When I
reached it, it had subsided to a creamy pool. Round and round then, and ever
contracting towards the button-like black bubble at the axis of that slowly
wheeling circle, like another exion did I revolve, till gaining that vital
center, the black bubble upward burst, and now liberated by reason of its
cunning spring, and owing to its great buoyancy rising with great force, the
coffin life boy shot lengthwise from the sea, fell over, and floated by my
replied. Boyed up by that coffin, for almost one whole day and night, I
floated on a soft and durge-like mane.
The unharming sharks they glided by as if with padlocks on their mouths. The
savage seahawks sailed with sheathed beaks. On the second day, a sail drew
near, nearer, and picked me up at last.
It was the devious cruising Rachel that in her retracing search after her
missing children only found another orphan.
The end.